[{"answer": "You're in charge.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 18, "question": "No?", "qSentId": 17}, {"answer": "I think it's totally appropriate to be on guard, because they are incredibly predatory fish.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 46, "question": "Was I right to feel scared?", "qSentId": 45}, {"answer": "-- is what it uses to pin down its target prey, which isn't a human being like us --", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 55, "question": "Yes?", "qSentId": 54}, {"answer": "-- it's the rays.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 57, "question": "But do they attack humans?", "qSentId": 56}, {"answer": "Rarely.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 59, "question": "ORGAN: Do hammerheads attack humans?", "qSentId": 58}, {"answer": "Well, there's a number of species that have been known to cross paths with people in a negative way.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 65, "question": "What are the most predatory of all the sharks?", "qSentId": 64}, {"answer": "I think the biggest misconception is that they are just a -- a hardwired eating machine.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 90, "question": "What is the biggest misconception about sharks, do you think?", "qSentId": 89}, {"answer": "Right.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 104, "question": "It would -- really, it would cut me open?", "qSentId": 103}, {"answer": "Myth.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 112, "question": "Are they naturally man-eaters?", "qSentId": 111}, {"answer": "Well, I think, like any predator, they'll take advantage of easy prey.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 117, "question": "Do they like it?", "qSentId": 116}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 123, "question": "-- on human flesh?", "qSentId": 122}, {"answer": "Some shark species actually can sink when they stop swimming.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 127, "question": "Is that true?", "qSentId": 126}, {"answer": "They have no bones.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 132, "question": "Sharks have no bones?", "qSentId": 131}, {"answer": "They're made out of cartilage, which is -- which is what they share in common with the skates and the stingrays.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 135, "question": "Literally no bones?", "qSentId": 134}, {"answer": "I don't know if that's true.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 146, "question": "Is that true?", "qSentId": 145}, {"answer": "ORWIN: You can get a frenzy.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 155, "question": "(INAUDIBLE) the -- the movie scenes when there's a sort of -- a lot of blood in the water and then you see a -- or a shark descending on them, is that, in reality, how it works?", "qSentId": 154}, {"answer": "Sharks actually can display some types of cannibalism.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 162, "question": "Do sharks eat each other?", "qSentId": 161}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 166, "question": "Really?", "qSentId": 165}, {"answer": "This right here, this is a spiny dog fish, or a spiny shark.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 171, "question": "What is this one?", "qSentId": 170}, {"answer": "This is one of the least dangerous species of sharks.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 184, "question": "How dangerous would that shark be?", "qSentId": 183}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 194, "question": "-- and you hear of rock salmon?", "qSentId": 193}, {"answer": "Well, I guess it depends the species of sharks.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 203, "question": "What's their favorite eating fish?", "qSentId": 202}, {"answer": "Absolutely.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 219, "question": "And let's come back and talk a little bit more about sharks, because everyone is quietly fascinated with them, aren't they?", "qSentId": 218}, {"answer": "Well, it's sort of an interesting question.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 232, "question": "Why do we need sharks?", "qSentId": 231}, {"answer": "Climate change certainly can have an impact on the populations of some species of sharks.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 242, "question": "Does climate change have any impact on the sharks' population?", "qSentId": 241}, {"answer": "Absolutely.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 247, "question": "Is the biggest threat to sharks and their future, as with so many animals, human?", "qSentId": 246}, {"answer": "Well, it -- again, depending on the species of shark.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 251, "question": "What do they do to you?", "qSentId": 250}, {"answer": "He'll hold very tightly.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 264, "question": "And does he -- does he clamp or rip?", "qSentId": 263}, {"answer": "You could see it.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 276, "question": "And you could see it?", "qSentId": 275}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 282, "question": "By a shark?", "qSentId": 281}, {"answer": "I think probably there are a number of creatures.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 293, "question": "What animal does the shark fear in the water, anything?", "qSentId": 292}, {"answer": "Absolutely.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 297, "question": "A shark would be scared of a dolphin?", "qSentId": 296}, {"answer": "They're incredible -- they have amazing defenses when a -- when dolphins feel threatened by sharks, they will plow at, you know, at torpedo speed into the side of that shark and actually --", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 300, "question": "Why?", "qSentId": 299}, {"answer": "-- kill.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 302, "question": "Really?", "qSentId": 301}, {"answer": "And orcas, killer whales have been known to take on sharks.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 310, "question": "-- a bull shark?", "qSentId": 309}, {"answer": "I think a great white may be afraid of other great whites.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 314, "question": "Is a great white scared of anything?", "qSentId": 313}, {"answer": "They have been known to fight each other.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 317, "question": "Do they fight each other?", "qSentId": 316}, {"answer": "Absolutely.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 330, "question": "So, this is a stingray tail?", "qSentId": 329}, {"answer": "That is the weapon of death.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 340, "question": "And this is where the sting comes?", "qSentId": 339}, {"answer": "Huge.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 352, "question": "And how big do they get, a stingray?", "qSentId": 351}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 362, "question": "-- to sting them?", "qSentId": 361}, {"answer": "It's a totally defensive mechanism.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 365, "question": "It's a defensive mechanism?", "qSentId": 364}, {"answer": "Oh, absolutely.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 369, "question": "Could you die of a stingray sting?", "qSentId": 368}, {"answer": "Well, the -- what the -- the reason why they're called witch's purses is actually because of this.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 389, "question": "Why are they sometimes called witches purse?", "qSentId": 388}, {"answer": "Exactly.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 399, "question": "And a skate is like a mini stingray without the stick?", "qSentId": 398}, {"answer": "This is a little baby that hatched out.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 411, "question": "It's a little baby, isn't it?", "qSentId": 410}, {"answer": "This is the mother of these babies.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 419, "question": "Is that the mother there?", "qSentId": 418}, {"answer": "They are not dangerous.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 425, "question": "The skate -- skates aren't dangerous, right?", "qSentId": 424}, {"answer": "This could -- if the water was warm, it could be in less than a year.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 442, "question": "And how long could that take to hatch?", "qSentId": 441}, {"answer": "Well, he's pretty big.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 467, "question": "How big is it -- how big is this alligator?", "qSentId": 466}, {"answer": "They were over hunted.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 485, "question": "And how did that happen?", "qSentId": 484}, {"answer": "And this is probably a couple of years old.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 505, "question": "How old is this?", "qSentId": 504}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 508, "question": "Seriously?", "qSentId": 507}, {"answer": "It was an illegal pet.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 511, "question": "How did it get there?", "qSentId": 510}, {"answer": "It is not true.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 518, "question": "Is that a myth?", "qSentId": 517}, {"answer": "ORWIN: It's not dangerous, but it certainly could hurt you.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 522, "question": "But even at that size, is it dangerous?", "qSentId": 521}, {"answer": "You can tell the way the -- the -- the snout is shaped.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 530, "question": "What is it?", "qSentId": 529}, {"answer": "I would -- to me, they're -- I will swim in alligator country if I feel the risks are low.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 535, "question": "Who's more dangerous, crocodiles or alligators?", "qSentId": 534}, {"answer": "Because I think you'd risk a chance of be being, you know, the early buffet of a -- of a crocodile --", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 538, "question": "Why?", "qSentId": 537}, {"answer": "I think they're remarkable predators.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 542, "question": "-- are the most dangerous of the reptiles, huh?", "qSentId": 541}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 553, "question": "I think it's Fred, right?", "qSentId": 552}, {"answer": "A lot of people, believe it or not, keep them as pets.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 559, "question": "How many people are keeping these things as pets?", "qSentId": 558}, {"answer": "Well, that's kind of a mystery.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 575, "question": "How long can they live?", "qSentId": 574}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 584, "question": "But they all look a bit docile until they kill you, right?", "qSentId": 583}, {"answer": "Well, if he was in predator mode, basically, what he would be doing is just sort of hunkered down like a submarine low to the water.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 587, "question": "What would he do?", "qSentId": 586}, {"answer": "Wow!", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 595, "question": "Do you see that?", "qSentId": 594}, {"answer": "He will basically hold on very, very tight.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 606, "question": "What will this do for you?", "qSentId": 605}, {"answer": "Oftentimes, they will drown you, if they don't crush you first, depending on your size.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 610, "question": "So they drown you first?", "qSentId": 609}, {"answer": "Well, you know --", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 614, "question": "Why are you so calm around something that could, at any moment, turn predatory?", "qSentId": 613}, {"answer": "All your nightmares are coming true.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 639, "question": "What have you got in there?", "qSentId": 638}, {"answer": "I'd ask for help, but I know I won't get it.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 649, "question": "How big is that?", "qSentId": 648}, {"answer": "This -- he's 15 feet long.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 660, "question": "How big is it?", "qSentId": 659}, {"answer": "You can buy them in pet shops.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 671, "question": "Where do people get these from a pet?", "qSentId": 670}, {"answer": "Well, they're a part of that living community.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 677, "question": "What do they do in the jungle that's so positive?", "qSentId": 676}, {"answer": "This animal is probably five or six years old.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 687, "question": "-- how old is this one?", "qSentId": 686}, {"answer": "ORWIN: I think they named it Buddha.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 689, "question": "Does she have a name?", "qSentId": 688}, {"answer": "It literally squeezes the life out of you.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 695, "question": "Is it as simple as that?", "qSentId": 694}, {"answer": "It is very possible that a large snake could kill a human.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 716, "question": "Do -- could they kill a human?", "qSentId": 715}, {"answer": "Because I know -- I -- I know his behavior.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 720, "question": "Why are you so comfortable around it?", "qSentId": 719}, {"answer": "Well, it would be coil up.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 725, "question": "What would it do to show that it's stressed?", "qSentId": 724}, {"answer": "I would say they don't.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 735, "question": "So if I were to ask you, do snakes have legs, what would you say?", "qSentId": 734}, {"answer": "Well, you know, in the Amazon, the Anaconda, which is a large boa.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 742, "question": "What is the biggest creature this kind of python could eat, who is in -- in the jungle?", "qSentId": 741}, {"answer": "No, this -- that's his chin and this is called buccal pumping.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 811, "question": "And this constant thing with its -- its -- what do you call it gut?", "qSentId": 810}, {"answer": "I think probably one of the most amazing moments for me was recently filming in New Zealand and actually coming face with a bird species that actually was extinct in the wild and they had rediscovered it.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 819, "question": "Of all the creatures that you've found in the ocean or seen, what's been the most amazing moment for you?", "qSentId": 818}, {"answer": "Absolutely, Piers.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 824, "question": "Could -- couldn't the public around the world be doing a lot more to help conserve the great creatures of the ocean?", "qSentId": 823}, {"answer": "Nothing.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 832, "question": "What do you think?", "qSentId": 831}, {"answer": "\"Sharks\" is our new book.", "docId": "130802pmt", "aSentId": 848, "question": "And the book is called \"Sharks\"?", "qSentId": 847}]